# **Darren M Smith**

Email: dxsmith12@soverin.net | Phone: 703.927.8456 | Chesterfield VA 23832

GitHub: https://github.com/thedern | Website: https://thedern.github.io | LinkedIn: https://linkedin.com/in/dxsmith12

#### **SUMMARY**

IT professional turned web developer with experience in e-commerce supporting both backend systems as well as frontend, customer facing applications. Highly motivated learner with a certification from University of Richmond Full Stack Web Development bootcamp. Possesses strong skills in frontend technologies such as html, css, javascript, and jQuery as well as skills in server-side technologies such as python and bash. Excited about useful and creative web design and its impact on people's lives.

#### **EDUCATION & CERTIFICATIONS**

University of Richmond, Richmond VA - Full Stack Web Development Bootcamp - 2019'

Intensive, project-based curriculum focused on full stack web development, specifically the MERN stack

CompTIA Cloud Essentials - Certification, 12/2017 AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner - Certification, 11/2017 CompTIA Security+ - Certification, 7/2016 CompTIA Network+ - Certification, 5/2017

Radford University, Radford VA - Biology Cum Laude - 1997

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

HTML/CSS; javascript; jQuery; node.js, python; jython; bootstrap 4; shell; sql; Firebase; Linux (RedHat, Ubuntu); Amazon Web Services; Apache/Tomcat Server; WebSphere; MuleSoft Anypoint Platform

## **APPLICATIONS BUILT**

#### **Lead Developer**

- **Barnyard Word Guess** A game developed for preschool aged children facilitating practice with the alphabet <a href="https://thedern.github.io/word\_guess\_game">https://thedern.github.io/word\_guess\_game</a>; Technologies: html/css/bootstrap/javascript
- **Gems** A blackjack-like numbers game <a href="https://thedern.github.io/unit\_4\_game">https://thedern.github.io/unit\_4\_game</a>; Technologies: html/css/bootstrap/javascript
- **Gif Search** An api driven app that provides a search interface for Giffs <a href="https://thedern.github.io/giftastic6">https://thedern.github.io/giftastic6</a>; Technologies: <a href="https://thedern.github.io/giftastic6">https://thedern.github.io/giftastic6</a>;
- Holiday Train Schedule An app that utilizes Firebase for persistent storage of a mock train station schedule https://thedern.github.io/trainschedule7; Technologies: html/css/bootstrap/javascript/Firebase

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## **Systems Engineer IV**

Advance Autoparts Inc.

2011-Present Richmond, VA

- Member of a team of IT professionals tasked with the deployment and maintenance of retail and wholesale e-commerce sites (advanceautoparts.com / advancecommercial.com) which generate over \$500 million in net sales annually.
- Develops python and jython utilities for the automation of applications server tasks as well as for research endeavors such as infrastructure analysis and web server log scraping
- Deploys web application code (html, css, js, java) to production e-commerce websites
- Maintains site's web and application server software, ensuring uptime and availability to customers
- Works closely with web application developers remediating code-related errors ensuring functionality and usability, protecting company revenue

## **Senior Middleware Administrator**

2010-2011

Federal Reserve IT (FRIT); Federal Reserve Bank of Richmond

Richmond, VA

- Technical support engineer for Federal Reserve banking systems internal web-based applications which provide services and support to the Nation's banking systems.
- Responsibilities included 24x7 support for web-based banking systems, technology roadmapping, systems design and implementation, technical documentation, and internal customer engagement/training.

#### **Consultant - Senior Systems Administrator**

2005-2010

Circuit City Stores Inc.

Richmond, VA

- Web-based application systems administrator supporting both internal web-based systems as well as the consumer-facing e-commerce site, *circuitcity.com*.
- Provided 24x7 support for *circuitcity.com* which included deploying code (html, css, js, and java) as well as ensuring site uptime and security.
- Work closely with developers remediating code-related errors ensuring functionality and usability, protecting company revenue
- Member of e-commerce 'Black Friday/Cyber Monday' support team ensuring website uptime and performance on most important retail days of the year.
- Internally, provided support to development teams during regular business hours via maintaining both web and application servers used for e-commerce application development.

## **About Me**

When not pounding away at the keyboard, enjoys adventure racing, hiking, mountain biking, gardening, yoga, Brazilian jiu-jitsu, as well as traditional Asian martial arts.